SANTOS DEVON R CTN1 USA USN

Summary of Qualifications

An accomplished Computer Networks Operations professional with over 6 years of experience while leading multiple mission efforts to meet high priority US Navy, US Army and National Requirements; seeking technical job roles to further expertise and experience as well as challenge myself within the cyber domain.

Clearance: Top Secret/SCI with CI Polygraph

Experience

Senior Enlisted Exploitation Analyst and Trainer at USCYBERCOM

2018 to 2021; Navy Information Operations Command Georgia, Fort Gordon, GA

- Project Lead for multiple Lines of Effort. Led and/or managed the execution of over 100 computer network operations spanning between six projects and two Combat Mission Teams.
- Senior Trainer for ARCYBER/JFHQ-C. Created a training program to increase qualification rate for new accessions and provide more workforce assets for entire branch.
- Supervised and mentored junior joint-servicemen and women as a Non-commissioned officer.
- Consistently conducted quick response analysis in support of world crisis events; efficiently managed and executed operations in support of CENTCOM's highest priority interests.
- Briefed senior officials/officers on the progress of critical network analysis projects and computer network operations.

Exploitation Analyst and Trainer at National Security Agency-Hawaii

2015 to 2018; Navy Information Operations Command Hawaii, Wahiawa, HI

- Project Lead. Conducted over 100 computer network operations to perform and enable collection of Foreign Intelligence in support of national security and US military requirements.
- Built network maps to visualize logical layouts of target networks.
- Drafted technical plans to conduct on-net cyber operations.
- Identified logical and physical security controls, analyzed information system defense posture, and conducted full risk assessments
- Tailored searches to efficiently query data warehouses for relevant information
- Managed administrative and technical training for section.
- Coordinated with branch leads between three NSA Field sites and facilitated a complete mission transfer in 2 weeks.

Initial Entry Trainee - US Navy

2014 to 2015; CID Corry Station, Pensacola, FL

- Learned and exercised full scope Computer Network Operations in a lab environment
- Completed Joint Cyber Analysis Course (JCAC) with Honors, which encompasses:
 - Systems Administration for Windows, *nix, and Cisco devices
 - Computational Mathematics
 - o C Programming & BASH/Python scripting
 - o Network Traffic Analysis and Threat Detection
 - o Network Reconnaissance and Penetration Testing
 - o Malware Analysis

Boatswain's Mate - US Navy

2012 to 2014; USS George Washington (CVN-73), Yokosuka, Japan

- Rigger for all deck evolutions, to include Underway Replenishment (Cargo, Food and Fuel)
- On-Scene leader for General Quarters/Damage Control Situations. Directed Firefighting, Flooding and Collision efforts in response to emergency casualties.
- Drove over 5,000 nautical miles as helmsman for aircraft carrier in the Western Pacific Ocean.
- Qualified six people in watch standing responsibilities as Over Instructor for watch section.

Technical Expertise

- Linux Operating Systems 6 yrs
- Windows Operating Systems 6 yrs
- Network Enumeration 6 yrs
- Vulnerability Analysis 6 yrs
- Packet Analysis/Wireshark 6 yrs
- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, Outlook, Visio) 6yrs
- VMware 6 yrs
- Kali Linux/Metasploit 6 yrs
- Cisco/MikroTik 6 yrs
- TCP/IP Network Design 6 yrs
- Ticketing Systems 6 yrs

Education

University of Maryland Global Campus - Adelphi, MD

2016 to Current

Associates Degree in Computer Studies; 44/60 credits completed. – expected December 2022 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Networks and Cybersecurity; currently hold a 3.05 GPA, with 76/120 credits completed.

National Cryptologic School

2015 to Current; full transcript available on request

Completed over 750 hours of course-work; courses of note include:

- Requirements and Targeting Immersion Program (CYBR3800)
- NET+ Boot Camp
- SEC+ Boot Camp
- Certified Ethical Hacker
- CCNA Boot Camp
- Analytic Tradecraft Fundamentals (NETA2108)

References available upon Request

Case number (RES-2020-05276)